June 1983
（殴る音）
ハァ…ハァ…
ハァ…
Spirited Away by the Demon \ NChapter One , The Beginning
When They Cry
Behind where I looked back
(who's there in the front)?
I raised my nails in the dark
(and slashed the night).
Raindrops become droplets of
blood and drip down the throat.
If you don't have
a place to go back to...
...then stop here on my finger.
I'll take you away
along with that finger.
To the unopenable
forest where cicadas cry.
You can't turn back anymore .
（圭一(けいいち)）ウ…ウ～ン…
ウ～ン…
Good morning .
（圭一）おはよう
（藍子(あいこ)）おはよう
Good morning .
I'm going .
（圭一）いってきま～す
Oh , Keiichi .
（藍子）ああ圭一
Thank Rena - chan for the pickles .
（藍子）レナちゃんに“お漬物
ありがとう”って伝えてね
Okay .
あいよ！
It's been one month since \ NI moved to Hinamizawa .
（圭一）
この雛見沢(ひなみざわ)に引っ越して１か月
For the first time ,\ NI learned that air can smell good .
空気にも味があることを
俺は初めて知った
Keiichi - kun !
（ﾚﾅ）圭一君おっはよう！
Good morning !
（圭一）相変わらず早(はえ)えな
You're early, as usual.
You could sleep in \ Nonce in a while .
たまにはのんびり
朝寝坊したっていいんだぜ
If I slept in , I'd make you wait .
お寝坊したら
圭一君待たせちゃうじゃない
そんときは置いてく
And I'd ditch you .
け…圭一君冷た～い！
Keiichi - kun , you're cold !\ NI always wait for you !
いつも 待っててあげてるのに…
サクサク置いてく
キリキリ置いてく
I'd just ditch you \ Nwithout any hesitation .
Why are you so cold ? Why ?
どうして冷たいんだろう？
だろう？
I'm kidding . I'd wait for sure .
ウソ　ちゃんと待ってるよ
アア…あ…ありがとう
T - Thanks ...
This weird one who easily \ Nblushes is Rena Ryugu .
（圭一）このすぐ真っ赤になって
ポ～ッとする変なヤツは竜宮(りゅうぐう)レナ
Oh, I have
a message from my mom.
Oh , I have \ Na message from my mom .\ NI've known her \ Nless than a month ...
まだ知り合って
ひと月もたってないが―
変わってるのは
名前だけじゃないことは―
Oh , I have \ Na message from my mom .\ N ... but I know her name isn't \ Nthe only weird thing about her .
" Thanks for the pickles ."\ N ... but I know her name isn't \ Nthe only weird thing about her .
よく分かる
N-No problem.
...but I know her name isn't
the only weird thing about her.
N - No problem .
どういたしましてフフッ…
You're welcome .
（魅音(みおん)）オッ！来た来た
遅いよ２人とも
There you are.
You're both late.
Good morning , Mi - chan !
魅(み)ぃちゃんおっはよう！
いつも遅いのはお前のほうだろう
You're the one who's always late .
圭ちゃんお久しぶり
何年ぶりだっけ？
Long time no see , Kei - chan .\ NHow many years was it ?
２日しか休んでねえよ
（魅音）アハハハッ…
I was absent for two days .
レナの律儀さとは別に
マイペースなヤツ
Unlike the conscientious Rena ,\ Nshe goes at her own pace .
Oh, really. You were so cute
the last time I saw you!
Unlike the conscientious Rena,
she goes at her own pace.
Oh , really . You were so cute \ Nthe last time I saw you !\ NMion Sonozaki .
こいつは園崎(そのざき)魅音　一応上級生で
クラスのリーダー役だ
What are you talking about?
Mion Sonozaki.
An upperclassman
who's like the class leader.
So how was it being \ Nback in the city ?\ NAn upperclassman \ Nwho's like the class leader .
（魅音）
どうだった？久しぶりの都会はさ
葬式で行っただけだぜ
慌ただしいだけだったよ
I only went for a funeral .\ NIt was just really busy .
So did you get what I asked for ?
（魅音）
…でさ探しといてくれた？
頼んどいたやつ
I told you I was at a funeral !
（圭一）
だから！俺は葬式に行ったの！
Hinamizawa is a small village ...
ここ雛見沢は小さな村で
学校どころかクラスも１つしかない
... so it only has \ None school with one class .
The class is mixed \ Nages and grades .
そのクラスも
年齢学年バラバラで
It's a lonely village with a total \ Nof about fifteen students .
全員足しても
15人いるかどうかという寒村ぶりだ
先生も１人
There's one teacher .
学年が違うごとに違うことを
教えなければいけないのだから―
It must be hard to teach different \ Nthings to each grade level .
大変だ
時には俺が先生に代わって
レナや魅音の勉強を見るハメになる
I sometimes end up teaching \ NRena and Mion in her place .
（ﾚﾅ）圭一君はお勉強教えるの
うまいね　分かりやすいよ
You're good at teaching .\ NIt's easy to understand .
When I start teaching ,\ NI lose my confidence ...
（圭一）
教える端から自信がなくなるよ
... since I realize how little I know .
自分の理解の浅さが分かるからな…
（魅音）人に教えるには―
They say you need to know it \ Nthree times better to teach it .
３倍 理解してなければ
ならないっていうしね
…ていうかさお前
学年１つ上だろう！
Actually , you're a grade higher .\ NWhy are you learning from me ?
なんで俺に教わってんだ？
（魅音）細かいことは気にしない
Don't worry about the details .
（圭一）アアッ…
（ﾚﾅ）ねえ圭一君
Hey , Keiichi - kun , do you have \ Nplans tomorrow ? Do you ?
あしたはさ
何か予定とかあるかな？ かな？
えっ？
（魅音）圭ちゃんさ…
You still can't find your way \ Naround Hinamizawa alone , right ?
まだこの雛見沢
１人じゃ回れないでしょう？
I guess .
そうだな　街へ行くのと
学校へ行く以外はまだ自信ないな
I'm still not sure how to get to \ Nplaces besides school and town .
Right , right .
そうそうそれでね
あしたね魅ぃちゃんとレナで―
So for tomorrow, Mi-chan and I...
... want to show you around \ NHinamizawa while taking a walk .
お散歩しながら
圭一君に雛見沢を―
案内してあげようよってことに
なって
レナお弁当作っていくから
どうかな？
I'll make boxed lunches .\ NInterested ?
もちろん行くでしょう？
You'll come , right ?
暇ならな
If I'm free .
何よその態度！
女の子が誘ってんじゃん！
What's with that attitude ?\ NA girl's asking you out !
暇ならな
（魅音）なっ…
If I'm free .
Keiichi - kun , aren't you free ?\ NAren't you ?
圭一君暇じゃないのかな？かな？
I'm free .
暇だ
（魅音）なっ！
I'm glad !
良かった
Hey , I see quite a difference \ Nin how you treat us here .
おうおう魅音さんとレナさんじゃ
随分と温度差がありますじゃん！
ベーッ！
（魅音）ムカッ！
Rena , let's go out \ Nalone tomorrow .
（圭一）レナ
あしたは２人きりで出かけような
If that's what you want .
（ﾚﾅ）圭一君がそれでいいなら
Hey , I was the one \ Nwho suggested the tour !
（魅音）ちょっと案内しようって
提案したのはあたし！
This is called Furude Shrine .
（ﾚﾅ）
ここはね古手(ふるで)神社っていうの
This place probably \ Nhas the best view .
多分
見晴らしがいちばんいい所かな
During the next break ,\ Nthere's going to be a festival here .
（魅音）次の休みは
ここで お祭りがあるからね
（圭一）ふ～ん…
じゃじゃ～ん！
Ta - dah ! Rena's deluxe \ Nboxed lunches , special version !
レナの特製弁当
スペシャルバージョンだよ
う～ん…すごい量だ
Gee , that's a lot .
（梨花(りか)）こんにちはです
（圭一）はぁ？
Hello .
（魅音）オッ！来た来た
Oh , there you are .
（圭一）沙都子(さとこ)に梨花ちゃん？
Satoko and Rika - chan ?
この２人は俺のクラスメートの
北条(ほうじょう)沙都子と古手(ふるで)梨花
These two are my classmates ,\ NSatoko Hojo and Rika Furude .
They're underclassmen of course .
…とはいっても
もちろん学年は下だけど
What's with all this excitement ?
（沙都子）
これは一体何の騒ぎですの？
Can't you tell ?
（圭一）見りゃ分かるだろう
We're about to enjoy Rena's \ Nhomemade boxed lunches .
これから
レナの手作り弁当に舌鼓だ
I can see that .
そんなの
見れば分かるでございますわ！
Why are you spreading \ Na mat in someone else's yard ?
どうして人さまのお庭で
ゴザなんか広げてますのよ？
The shrine is public !\ NDon't think it's yours !
神社は公共の場所だぞ
勝手に独占するな！
Keiichi's right .\ NLet's make this everyone's yard .
（梨花）圭一の言うとおりですよ
みんなのお庭にしますです
ク～ッ！やっぱり
梨花ちゃんはいい子だなぁ
Rika's really a good girl !
座りなそこ！一緒に食べよう
Sit over there !\ NLet's eat together !
（口笛）
（沙都子）しょうがないですわね
I guess I have no choice .\ NI will join you all .
せっかくですから
私もご一緒してさし上げましてよ
There's no room for you \ Nto sit and not enough food .
お前に座る場所はないし
食べる分もない
ベーッ！
（沙都子）なんですって？
What did you say ?
（沙都子）ンンッ！
（圭一）や～い や～い！
（ﾚﾅ）大丈夫だよ
It's okay . There's enough \ Nfor Satoko - chan too .
沙都子ちゃんの分も
ちゃんとあるから
Nope , I'm going \ Nto have Satoko's share .
（圭一）
ない！沙都子の分も俺がいただく
I won't let you !
（沙都子）
そんなことは許せませんの！
Here are the chopsticks .
はい お箸です
（沙都子）
いっただっきま～すですわ
I'm going to eat !
俺だっていただきますだ！
Me too ! I'm eating too !
It's nice to be young .
いやはや若いっていいねえ
Please eat a lot .\ NThere's enough for everyone .
いっぱい食べてね
ちゃんとみんなの分あるから
The hamburger steak is mine !
（圭一）ハンバーグいただき！
I am not letting you have it !
そのハンバーグは渡しませんわ！
（殴る音）
ウワッ！
Elbowing's against the rules ...
（圭一）肘は反則だろう…
Oh , we had rules ?
（沙都子）
あらルールなんてありましたの？
Eating lunch with \ Neveryone is so fun ! So fun !
（ﾚﾅ）みんなで お弁当
楽しいな 楽しいな！
（梨花）
レナのお弁当はおいしいのです
Rena's boxed \ Nlunches are delicious .
（魅音）
んじゃ今日のところはこれで解散
Okay , let's call it a day .
レナに圭ちゃんまたあしたね
Rena , Kei - chan , till tomorrow .
Thanks for today , Mion .\ NIt was fun .
（圭一）魅音今日はありがとうな
楽しかったぜ
（ﾚﾅ）またあしたね
（魅音）うん！
See you tomorrow !
圭一君も今日は
つきあってくれてありがとう
Thanks for coming with us today ,\ NKeiichi - kun . Did you have fun ?
楽しかった？
ああ楽しかった
Yeah , I did .
まだ家(うち)に帰るのが惜しいくらいだぜ
So much that I don't \ Nfeel like going home yet .
あっじゃあさちょっとだけ
寄り道してもいいかな？かな？
Then can we stop by \ Nsomewhere ? Can we ?
（圭一）寄り道？遠いのか？
Stop by somewhere ? Is it far ?
（ﾚﾅ）
ちょっと歩くけどすぐ済むから
We'll walk a bit , but it \ Nwon't take long . This way !
こっち こっち！
（圭一）ああっ…
（ﾚﾅ）アハハッ！
今日は久しぶりだから
何があるかな？何があるかな？
Since it's been a while ,\ NI wonder what's there . I wonder .
It's been a while ?
（圭一）“久しぶり”って…
You wanted to come \ Nto this garbage dump ?
レナの用はこのゴミの山かよー！
ゴ…ゴミじゃないよ
レナにとっては宝の山だもん！
I - It's not garbage !
To me ,\ Nit's a mountain of treasure !
わあ新しい山だ
ワクワクワクワク！
A new mountain.
Hurray!
Hey , wait !
（圭一）おい待てよ！
ウワッ！いたたた…
Ow ...
You can just stay there !
いいよ圭一君はそこにいて
すぐ済むから！
I'll be done soon!
Are all country girls this tough ?
（圭一）さすが田舎育ち…
かなわん
（圭一）ハァ…
うん？
（富竹(とみたけ)）あっ…
ンンッ！ ハァ…
（富竹）ああびっくりした
You surprised me .
T - That's my line !
（圭一）
そ…それはこっちのセリフだよ
（富竹）あっごめんごめん
驚かすつもりはなかったんだ
Sorry , I didn't mean to scare you .
君は雛見沢の人かい？
（圭一）は…はぁ…
Are you from Hinamizawa ?
Y - Yes ...
僕は富竹　フリーのカメラマン
I'm Tomitake,
a freelance photographer.
I occasionally \ Ncome to Hinamizawa .
この雛見沢にはたまに来るんだ
Isn't it polite to ask permission \ Nbefore taking a picture ?
（圭一）写真ってのは―
被写体に断ってから撮るのが
礼儀なんじゃないんスかね？
あっごめんごめん
メーンは野鳥の撮影でね
Sorry , I usually take \ Npictures of wild birds .
I've never asked them before .
今まで断ったためしがないんだよ
ハハハハッ…
ハハッ…あっいや…
（ﾚﾅ）圭一君！
Keiichi - kun !
Sorry for making you wait !\ NI'm almost done !
（ﾚﾅ）待たせてごめんね
もう終わりにするから
You had company ?
（富竹）連れがいたのかい？
彼女は
あんな所で何をしているんだい？
What's she doing there ?
Who knows ?
さあね？
昔殺して埋めたバラバラ死体でも
確認してるんじゃないッスか？
Maybe she's checking out \ Nan old corpse she chopped up .
（富竹）イヤな事件だったね
It was a horrible crime .
腕が１本
まだ見つかってないんだろう？
They still haven't found \ None of the arms , right ?
えっ？何の…
What ...
（ﾚﾅ）
アハハッ！圭一君お待たせ！
Thanks for waiting , Keiichi - kun !
じゃ
馬に蹴られる前に退散するかな
Well , I should go \ Nbefore I get kicked out .
驚かせてすまなかったね圭一君
Sorry for scaring you , Keiichi - kun .
（ﾚﾅ）待ったかな？かな？
Did you wait ? Did you ?
Keiichi - kun ?
圭一君？
えっ？
あっ…でどうだったんだ？
How did it go ?
Did you find anything ?
（圭一）
掘り出し物は見つかったか？
うん！聞いて聞いて
あのねあったのケンタくん人形！
Listen , listen !\ NI found a Kenta doll !
A Kenta doll ?
ケンタくん人形って…あれか？
You mean that ?
“ケンタくんフライドチキン”の
店の前に必ず置いてある―
That life - sized model that's always \ Noutside Kenta Fried Chicken ?
あの等身大人形の？
Yeah , the Kenta doll !
そうケンタくん！
はぅ…かぁいいよ
お持ち帰りしたい！
It's so cute !\ NI want to take him home !
フフッ…あれはゴミだろう
That's trash , right ?
お持ち帰りしたきゃ
してもいいんだぜ
If you want to take it ,\ NI'm sure you could .
The Kenta doll is trapped \ Nunder a pile of junk .
ケンタくん
ゴミの山の下敷きになってるの
簡単には掘り出せないよ
I can't easily dig him out .
I'll help you tomorrow .
あした俺も手伝ってやるよ
（ﾚﾅ）えっ？
弁当の恩返しってことでさ
In exchange for lunch today .
あ…ありがとう
Thanks !
Keiichi - kun will help ...
圭一君が手伝ってくれる…
ケンタくんをお持ち帰りできる！
I'll get to take \ Nthe Kenta doll home !
Hey , Rena , did something \ Nhappen here in the past ?
なあレナ
ここで昔何かあったのか？
あっ…
ダムの工事をやってたんだって
I heard they were building a dam .
I don't know too much about it .
詳しくは知らないけど
They were building a dam ?
ダムの工事？
例えばさ
その工事中に何かあったとか
Did something happen during \ Nconstruction , like an accident ?
事故とか…
I don't know .
知らない
（圭一）えっ？
レナ去年までよそに住んでたの
I was living \ Nsomewhere else till last year .
You were a transfer student too ?
レナも転校生だったのか
俺はてっきり…
I assumed ...
So I don't know much about what \ Nhappened before then , sorry .
だからね
それ以前のことはよく知らないの
ごめんね
（圭一）ああそうか
Oh , okay .
When They Cry
- Bye !\ N - See you later !
（女の子）さようなら
（男の子）またね
Let's see ...
（魅音）
さてと今日は会則にのっとり―
I would like to act \ Naccording to our rules ...
部員の諸君に是非を問いたい
... and debate the merits of inviting \ NKeiichi Maebara to our club !
彼前原(まえばら)圭一君を
新たな部員として―
我らの部活動に加えたいのだが
いかがだろうか？
No objections !
レナは異議な～し！
Ha ha ha
Can the peasant \ Nkeep up with me ?
貧民風情が
私の相手を務められるかしら？
Satoko and I agree too .
ボクも沙都子も賛成しますですよ
It's unanimous !\ NCongrats , Keiichi Maebara !
全会一致！おめでとう前原圭一君
君に我が部への入部を許可する！
I'll allow you to join!
Hey , explain this !\ NWhat's this club ?
こら！順を追って説明しろ
何の部活だ？
Besides , I never said I'd join !
大体が俺は
まだ“入る”とは言ってないぞ！
え～我が部はだな
複雑化する社会に対応するため―
Our club tries to counter \ Nthis complicated society ...
... and in prosperity or adversity ,\ Nour activities are decided by ...
活動ごとに提案される
さまざまな条件下―
時には順境 あるいは逆境から
いかにして…
つまりみんなで
ゲームして遊ぶ部活なのです
Basically , we play \ Ngames in our club .
I get it .
ようやく分かった
（魅音）先に断っとくけど…
I'll make it clear first .\ NWe don't play games like house .
ままごと遊びみたいな
レベルじゃないからね
You'd better do your best .
本気でかかったほうがいいよ
I - Isn't having fun enough ?\ NDon't threaten me ...
た…楽しくやればいいじゃねえか
そうすごむなよ
（魅音）甘い！
Weak !
会則第１条“狙うのは１位のみ”
Article 1: Strive only for first !
I won't allow that \ Nstance in a game !
“遊びだから”なんていう
いいかげんなプレーは許さない！
Article 2: To do that , putting forth \ Nall possible effort is required .
会則第２条“そのためには
あらゆる努力をすること”が―
義務づけられておりますのよ
（圭一）分かった分かった
I get it .
Complex games will put \ Nhim at a disadvantage ...
じゃ難しいゲームは
圭ちゃんに不利になるから…
... so let's play a game \ Neverybody understands .
今日は
誰にでも分かるゲームにしよう
How about ordinary old maid ?
スタンダードに
トランプのジジ抜きはどう？
（圭一）余裕だぜ！
Piece of cake .
For a punishment game , first \ Nplace can order last place around .
（魅音）
罰ゲームは１位がビリに１コ命令
この辺でどうかな？
How's that ?
Bring it on .
上等でございますわ
Okay , let's shuffle the cards .
（魅音）じゃカードを切って…
（ﾚﾅ）１枚抜くね
I'll take this one .
These cards are pretty worn .
このトランプ結構傷物だな
まさかみんなには―
Don't tell me you all know which \ Ncard is which from the scratches .
その傷でそこに伏せたカードが
分かってるとか？
（ﾚﾅたち）ヘヘヘヘッ…
（圭一）ちょ…ちょっと待て！
H - Hold on !
That's not fair !
そんなんありかよ！
Article 2: Putting forth all \ Npossible effort is required .
会則第２条“勝つためには
あらゆる努力をすること”ですわ
Some cards are really distinct ,\ Nso you'll notice them fast .
いくつかのカードは特徴的だから
圭一君もすぐに覚えられるよ
B - Bring it on ! Don't think \ Nthat this'll be a handicap !
じょ…上等だぜ
この程度でハンデになると思うなよ
ハハハッ！
圭ちゃんの手札を右から言うよ
I'll read your cards \ Nfrom right to left .
Three , four , nine , jack , queen .
（魅音）
３４９ジャッククイーン
グワーッ！
By the way , the odd card \ Nis the jack of diamonds .
ちなみに
ジジは ダイヤのジャックなのです
ウワーッ！
どうカードを入れ替えたって
見え見えですわ
It doesn't matter how you \ Nshuffle them , I can still tell .
フフン…
I'm out !
（梨花）上がりですの！
お…鬼だ　こいつらは鬼だ…
Y - You're evil .
Just evil.
Rena's not evil , right ?
レナは鬼じゃないよな？
S - Sorry , Keiichi - kun .
ご…ごめんね圭一君
こっちが
ハートの３だよね？
This is the three of hearts , right ?
上がり！
I'm out .
ウワーッ！
う～ん…
（ﾚﾅ）や…やっぱりさ…
It's unfair to him if we \ Ndon't play with a new deck ...
きれいなトランプでやらないと
圭一君に不公平だよ
It's fine . He's a man .
いいの いいの
圭ちゃんだって男だし
これくらいの逆境は
はね返せるよね？
I'm sure you can \ Nendure some adversity .
You can do it .
ファイトオーです
（圭一）う～ん…
Come on , Keiichi . Don't hide it .
ほら圭ちゃん隠さない隠さない
This scratched one is \ Nthe two of diamonds , right ?
（魅音）
この傷が確かダイヤの２だったよね
あれ？
Huh ?
あっ魅ぃちゃんが
カード間違えるなんて珍しいね
It's rare for you \ Nto make a mistake , Mi - chan .
T - That's not it . Kei - chan ...
ち…違う
圭ちゃんあんたまさか…
Did you ...
ハハハハッ！
引っ掛かったな園崎魅音！
I got you , Mion Sonozaki !
You somehow forged \ Nthe two of diamonds ?
ダイヤの２を
偽装したというんですの？
あ…味なマネを
するでございますわね
You made a witty move .
You got them back , Keiichi .
圭一一矢を報いましたです
（圭一）ヘヘッ！
You did it ! It was \ Na close game ! It was !
やったね圭一君
大善戦だよ！だよ！
I knew you could do it .
さすが
あたしが見込んだだけのことはある
I never expected you \ Nto think of something like this .
こんな手を思いつくとは
圭ちゃんさすがだよ
ウフフッ…
Except you're too late .
…とはいっても
ちょっと手遅れだったようですわね
I'm pretty much \ Nset in last place ...
まあ ビリは確定だけどさ
最後に
魅音から１本取れたから大満足かな
... but I was able to get \ Nback at Mion , so I'm satisfied .
そんじゃ
ビリの圭ちゃんには罰ゲームだねえ
Then let's do the punishment \ Ngame since you're last .
今日は部活の初日だし
ソフトなのからいこうかなぁ？
Since it's your first day in \ Nthe club , maybe I'll go easy .
I wouldn't want you to stop \ Ncoming to school all of a sudden .
（魅音）いきなり
登校拒否になられても困るしねえ
ウフフフッ…
（圭一）あっ！な…なに？
What ?
ほ～れ…
Hey ...
ほ～れ！
（圭一）アアッ…
Hey ...
S - Stop !
や…やめろー！
ケンタくん人形？
A Kenta doll ?
I see .
なるほど！それでレナのヤツ
飛んで帰っちゃったのか
That's why Rena took off so fast.
Thinking that thing is cute ...\ NShe's pretty weird .
あんなのがかわいいなんて
変わってるよなレナも
Weird hobbies too , but once \ Nshe finds something cute ...
（魅音）趣味も変わってるけど
レナのヤツいったん
“かわいいモード”に入っちゃうと
... she becomes \ Noblivious to everything else .
後先 見えなくなっちゃうからね
（圭一）
あそこさ…ダムの工事現場
About that place ...\ NThe dam construction site ...
Something happened \ Nthere in the past , right ?
何かあったんだろう？昔
Yeah .
あったよ
突然“ダム作る”って―
Government officials suddenly \ Ncame to evict us and build a dam .
役人どもが一方的に
立ち退きを迫ってきて…
Evict you ?
（圭一）一方的に？
だから闘ったんだよ村のみんなで
That's why we fought .\ NEveryone in the village .
闘わなければ今ごろ
村はダムの底に沈んでいたんだ
If we hadn't , this village \ Nwould've been underwater now .
（圭一）
よく勝てたな　相手は国だろう？
I'm impressed you won .\ NIt was against the government .
The village's leader and powerful \ Npeople petitioned together .
（魅音）村長や村の有力者たちがね
方々に陳情した
東京にも行ったし
いろんな政治家に根回しもした
They went to Tokyo and \ Nnegotiated with the politicians .
While doing all that ,\ Nthe plans got withdrawn .
そうしているうちに
計画は撤回されたんだよ
It was our perfect victory .
あたしたちの完全勝利だった
ハハハハッ…
ふ～ん…暴力沙汰とかには
ならなかったのか？
Were there any violent \ Ncrimes because of it ?
Like assault or murder ...
傷害事件とか…
殺人…
なかった
There weren't .
I - I see .
じゃまたあしたね
See you tomorrow .
圭ちゃんそれ
家に帰るまで消しちゃダメだからね
Kei - chan , you'd better not \ Nerase that until you get home .
わ…分かってるよ消さねえよ！
I know ! I won't erase it !
よいしょ！よいしょ！
Hey , Rena !
（圭一）ようレナ！
（ﾚﾅ）ハッ…
あっ！
（圭一）精が出ますな
Working hard , huh ?
Keiichi - kun !\ NWhat are you doing here ?
圭一君どうしたの？こんな所へ
事故発生の緊急通報を受け
参上しました
I got urgent info about \ Nan accident and have come .
Where is the injured person ?
負傷者はどこでありますか？
えっ？事故って？
Accident ?
I heard that a Kenta doll \ Nis buried alive in the dumpster .
ケンタくん人形が―
ゴミ山に生き埋めになっているとの
通報でしたが…
な…なんだびっくりした
O - Oh , that .
You surprised me.
So where's the Kenta doll ?
…でどこだよ？ケンタくんは
Oh , sorry ! Here , here !
あっごめん
ここここ！ほら…
Here , can you see it \ Nthrough this crack ?
この隙間から…見える？
Gee , he's totally buried alive .
（圭一）
こりゃホントに生き埋めだな
We might need an axe \ Nor saw to get it out .
本気でやるなら オノとか
ノコギリが要るかもしれねえな
あっちょっと待っててねっ？
（圭一）えっ？
Just hold on , okay ?
Hey !
（圭一）おい！
（富竹）イヤな事件だったね
It was a horrible crime .
腕が１本
まだ見つかってないんだろう？
They still haven't found \ None of the arms , right ?
Hinamizawa worker lynch death
（圭一）あった…
Hinamizawa worker lynch death \ NThere it is !
“雛見沢ダムで悪夢の惨劇”
Nightmare tragedy \ Nat Hinamizawa Dam .
“リンチ”“バラバラ殺人”
Lynched and hacked to pieces.
They beat the victim with hatchets \ Nand pickaxes in cold blood .
“犯人たちは
被害者をナタやツルハシで―”
“めった打ちにして惨殺し
更にオノで遺体を―”
Further , they cut the corpse \ Ninto six parts with an axe ...
“頭部両腕両足胴体の
６つに分割”
... the head , arms , legs , and torso .
“犯人のうち１人は
いまだ逃走中”
One of the murderers \ Nis still on the loose .
あっ！
（ﾚﾅ）知らない
I don't know .
なかった
There weren't .
There really was one ...
やっぱりあったんだ…
In retrospect , those noisy \ Ncicadas at that moment ...
（圭一）あのときうるさいほどに
鳴いていたひぐらしは―
今にして思えば
これから始まる全てのことを―
... were probably trying to warn \ Nme of all the events to come .
俺に
教えようとしていたのかもしれない
Of all the things that \ Nwere about to happen .
これから起こる全てのことを…
To get my happiness ,\ NI had done everything ...
...but had done nothing
to be blamed and accused of.
The sound of footsteps
became louder every day.
Then I noticed the fact
there was no time.
I was a believer in life,
to be myself always.
And was asking
whether I would be alive.
Give me a reason
why not to adopt in this way.
Or judge me to be guilty
of so many incurable sins.
Tell me why or why not?
Complaining way too much.
Maybe I overlooked
something fatal for me.
Preview
Preview \ NCan you believe \ Nin things you can see ?
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）
信じられるの？目に見えること
Can you believe
in things you can see?
Can you believe in living ?
信じられるの？息づくこと
信じられるの？私のこと
Can you believe in me ?
「ひぐらしのなく頃に」
When They Cry .
Spirited Away by the Demon \ NChapter Two , The Secret \ NSpirited Away by the Demon \ NChapter Two , The Secret .
あなたは信じられますか？
Spirited Away by the Demon
Chapter Two, The Secret
Can you believe it?